Now that we've learned more about neural networks,
NNの詳細やその効率的な
and how to train them efficiently,
トレーニング方法を学びました
and get the most generalization out of them,
最適な一般化も行いました
let's now talk about multi-class neural networks
次はマルチクラスのNNを説明し
when working with multi-class classification problems.
マルチクラス分類の問題を扱います
Here again, is the sigmoid function.
またシグモイド関数です
Which gives us calibrated probabilities.
調整済み確率を得られます
It's useful in the legitimate regression for binary class problems,
これは2項分類問題の正規回帰で役立ちます
or I can find the probability in the positive class,
または正クラスの確率が見つかります
where one minus that,
その確率を1から引くと
it's probably to be in the negative class.
負クラスに入ります
What then do we do when we have more than two classes?
クラスが3つ以上ある場合はどうしますか？
There are lots of multi-class problems.
多数のマルチクラス問題があります
This example is of ticket types in an Opera hall.
この例はオペラ劇場のチケットの種類です
Perhaps the model is for the seat type to recommend.
モデルは推奨する座席の種類です
Let's say there are four places to sit,
座席は4種類あるとします
in the pit, in stalls,
ピット、ストール
in a circle, or in a suite.
サークル、スイートです
If I want a probability for each of these seat types,
各座席の種類の確率を得たいなら
I can't just use a normal binary classification because I have too too many classes.
クラスが多すぎるので 通常の2項分類は使えません
If pit is my positive class,
ピットが正クラスなら
then what is this negative class?
負クラスは？
What do I do with the remaining classes?
残りのクラスはどうしますか？
One idea is to transform the problem from multi-class classification,
考えられるのはマルチクラス分類問題から
to many binary classification problems.
複数の2項分類問題への変換です
A method to do this is the one verse all or one verse rest approach.
これは「1対全部」または「1対残り」手法です
In this approach, we'll iterate through each class.
この手法では各クラスを繰り返し処理します
For each iteration, that class with the positive class,
各繰り返しで あるクラスを正クラスにし
and then where all the remaining classes will be lumped together into the negative class.
残りの全クラスをまとめて負クラスに入れます
In this way, I am predicting the probability of being in the positive class,
このようにして正クラスに入る確率を予測し
and conversely the probability of not being in the other classes.
反対に他のクラスに入らない確率を予測します
It is important that we output our pretty probability,
重要なことは 出力するのは確率であり
and not just the class level.
クラスレベルではないことです
So that we don't create ambiguities if
そのため1つのサンプルに対して
multiple classes are predicted for a single sample.
マルチクラスの予測では 曖昧度が作成されません
Once the model trained for each class being selected as the positive one,
正クラスに選択した各クラスを モデルでトレーニングしたら
we moved to the most valuable part of Machine Learning; predictions.
機械学習の最も重要な部分に移動しました 予測です
To make a prediction, you send your predictions sample
予測でトレーニング済みの2項分類モデルにより
through each of the trained binary classification models.
予測サンプルを送ると
Then the model that produces the highest probability or confidence score,
モデルが最高の確率または信頼スコアを生成し
we would choose as the overall predicted class.
私たちが全体的な予測済みクラスを選択します
Although this seems like a great solution,
これは素晴らしい解決策に思えますが
it comes with several problems.
複数の問題が伴います
First, the skill that the confidence score is might
まず信頼スコアというスキルは
be different for each of the binary classification models,
各2項分類モデルによって異なるため
which biases our overall prediction.
全体的な予測に偏りが生じます
However, even if that isn't the case,
ただしそうでない場合でも
each of the binary classification models,
2項分類モデルでは
see very unbalanced data distributions since for each one,
データ分布が非常に不均衡になります 各クラスの負クラスは
besides the one that is currently marked for the positive class.
クラスを除く他の全クラスの合計になるためです
A possible fix for this imbalance problem is the one verse one method.
この不均衡問題を修正できるのは 「1対1」方法です
Here, instead of having a model for each class,
ここにあるのは各クラスのモデルではなく
there is a model for each binary combination of the classes.
クラスの二元組み合わせモデルです
If there are any classes,
任意のクラスがある場合
this means that there would be n times n minus one,
n x (n - 1)を2で割った数だけ
over two models so of order n squared.
モデルが存在します n位の2乗になります
Already for four classes in our example that is six models,
この例の4クラスではモデルは6つですが
but if I had a thousand classes,
画像のコンペティションのように
like image that competition,
クラスが1000あったら
there would be 499,500 models.
モデルは499,500になります
Wow! Each model essentially outputs a vote for its predicted label,
各モデルが予測済みラベルに対して1票出力し
plus one or plus zero for the positive class label of each model.
各モデルの正クラスラベルに+1または+0します
Then all the votes are accumulated and the class that has the most wins.
すべての票が累計され 得票数が最大のクラスが勝ちになります
However, this doesn't fix the ambiguity problem,
しかしこれでは曖昧性問題が解決しません
because based on the input distribution,
入力分布に基づくと
it could end up having the same number of votes for different classes.
異なるクラスの得票数が同じになりうるためです
So, is there any way to do multi-class classification without these major drawbacks?
こうした大きな欠点のないマルチクラス分類の 実行方法はあるのでしょうか？
An idea could be to use the one verse all approach with Neural Networks,
考えられるのはNNを使用した 「1対全部」方法で
where instead of having multiple models for each class,
各クラスに複数のモデルを作成する代わりに
there is one model with a unique output for each possible class.
考えうる各クラスに固有の出力を持つ モデルを1つ作成します
We can train this model on a signal of ''my class'' verse ''all
各例に対してこのモデルを 「特定のクラス」対「他の全クラス」の
Therefore, we need to be careful in how we design our labels.
そのためラベルの設計には注意が必要です
Instead of having just a one for our true class,
trueクラスに1つだけ作成せずに
we will have a vector of length of the number of classes,
クラスの数の長さのベクトルを作成します
where our true classes correspond it'll be one,
ここでtrueクラスに当たるのは1
and the rest will be zero.
残りは0になります
This way, you will reward this corresponding sigmoid neuron for the true class,
このようにtrueクラスに当たる シグモイドニューロンが1に近づいたら
if it gets too close to one,
報酬を与え
it will punish the other sigmoid neurons if they also get close to one.
他のニューロンが1に近づいたら罰を与えます
With a higher error to be back propagated back through the network of their weights.
誤差が大きければ重みのネットワークを通じて 誤差逆伝送を行います
However, we may have problems with millions of new classes,
ただし新しい数百万のクラスには 問題が生じる場合があります
since we will have millions of output neurons.
数百万の出力ニューロンです
Thus millions of loss calculations,
数百万の損失計算の後に
followed by millions of errors being back-propagated through the network.
数百万の誤差が生じ誤差逆伝搬が行われます
Very computationally expensive.
計算コストが高額になります
Is there a better way?
もっといい方法は？
If we simply add an additional constraint,
単に制約を追加すると
the sum of outputs equals one.
出力の合計が1になります
Then it allows the output to be interpreted as probabilities.
これで出力が確率として解釈されます
This normalizing function is called Softmax.
この正規化関数をソフトマックスと呼びます
At each node, we find the exponential of W times X,
各ノードには W x X + bを
plus b and then divide by the sum of all the nodes.
全ノードの合計で割った指数関数があります
This ensures all nodes are between zero and one,
これで全ノードが0と1の間になり
and that the total probability equals one as it should.
全確率が1になります
This way, for each example,
このように各例で
you will get a normalized probability for each class,
各クラスの正規化確率を得られます
where you can then take that augmax to find the class,
次にargmaxでクラスを探します
the higher probability as your predicted label.
予測したラベルより高い確率です
In TenserFlow, we calculate our logits in
TensorFlowではWとXの適用メッシュ
our final layer as a mesh of application of W and X,
偏りノードとして最終層のロジットを計算し
the biased node, add to the result if one exists.
1がある場合は結果に追加します
This will give us a tensor shape of batch size for the number of classes.
これでクラスの数のバッチサイズが テンソル形状になります
Our labels are one hot encoded as we talked about previously,
ラベルがワンホットエンコーディングされ
where the true class gets a one,
各例のtrueクラスが1
and the other classes get zero for each example.
他のクラスが0を取得します
Therefore, also having the shape of tenser,
そのためクラスの数ごとの
of batch size, by the number of classes.
バッチサイズのテンソル形状にもなります
Note, because we are using TensorFlow,
TensorFlowの
the labels can actually be soft.
ラベルはソフトになります
What I mean by this is,
つまり
even though the classes are still mutually exclusive,
クラスが相互に排他的であっても
the probabilities need not be.
確率はその必要がありません
If you had three classes, for example,
たとえばクラスが3つあったら
your mini batch could have been one with its labels be 0.15,
ミニバッチはそのラベルが
They are not one hot encoded, however,
ワンホットエンコーディングでなくても
there are still a valid probability distribution since they sum to one.
合計すると1になるため これらは有効な確率分布です
Finally, we compare our logits with our labels using softmax cross entropy with logits.
softmax_cross_entropy_with_logits でロジットをラベルと比べます
It will get a result in tensor of shape, batch size.
結果は形状のテンソル、バッチサイズになります
In TensorFlow, 1.5 plus a version two of
TensorFlow 1.5+では この関数のv2が作成され
To get the average loss for that mini batch,
ミニバッチの平均損失を得るには
just use reduced mean on the output.
出力でreduce_meanを使用します
For convenience, TensorFlow has another function you can use instead to
便宜のためTensorFlowでは
In this case, we do away with the one high encoding,
この場合ワンハイエンコーディングまたは
or soft encoding of our labels,
ソフトエンコーディングを捨て
and instead just provide the index of
ゼロとクラス数から1を引いた数の間の
the true class between zero and the number of classes minus one.
trueクラスのインデックスを渡します
This means that our labels are now a tensor of shape, batch size.
つまりラベルは形状のテンソル、バッチサイズに なります
The output of the function is still the same as before as a tensor of shape, batch size.
関数の出力はまだ以前の形状のテンソル バッチサイズと同じです
I will still just reduce mean that tensor to get the average loss of the mini batch.
それでもそのテンソルのreduce_meanで ミニバッチの平均損失を求めます
Remember, for both softmax functions,
両方のソフトマックス関数では
we are only using them because our classes are mutually exclusive.
クラスが相互に排他的なため これらのみを使用します
For instance, image one is only a picture of a dog,
たとえば画像1は犬のみの写真で
and image two is only a picture of a cat.
画像2は猫のみの写真ですが
However, what if image three is a picture of both a dog and a cat?
画像3が犬と猫の両方の写真だとしたら どうしますか？
And for my ML problem,
そしてML問題では
I want to know that.
それを知りたいと思います
Using softmax, I will get a probability for each one,
ソフトマックスを使って各確率を得ますが
but I will take the augmax of it as my label.
そのargmaxをラベルとします
Therefore, depending on my image in my model,
そのためモデルの画像に応じて
it might label as a dog,
ラベルが犬になったり
or it might label as a cat.
猫になったりします
This is no good, because I want to know if both are in there,
これは使えません 知りたいのは 両方が写っているかどうかと
and if there are any other classes in there as well.
他のクラスがあるかどうかです
This is a multi-class multi-label classification problem.
これはマルチクラスマルチラベル分類問題です
In this case, I want the probability of each class from zero to one.
ここでは 0から1の各クラスの確率が必要です
Fortunately, TensorFlow is a nifty function that does just that,
TensorFlowはこれを行うのに 適した関数です
called sigmoid cross entropy with logits,
sigmoid_cross_entropy_with_logitsは
which returns a batch size by number of classes tensor.
クラス数のテンソルごとにバッチサイズを 返します
We need to evaluate every output node for every example.
各例の各出力ノードを評価する必要があります
Of course, every output node means also the weights that lead up to it.
各出力ノードはそこにつながる重みも意味します
So, a single step of 100 output node network,
1ステップの出力ノードネットワーク100個は
is like a hundred steps of a single output network.
100ステップの出力ネットワーク1つと同じです
Hugely expensive and hard to scale for a very large number of classes.
非常に高価で クラスが非常に多い場合 スケーリングが困難です
We need some way to approximate this softmax,
このソフトマックスの近似値を求め
that we can reduce some of the competition costs for very large multi-class problems.
巨大なマルチクラス問題の計算コストを 削減できる方法が必要です
Fortunately, aproximate versions of softmax exist.
ソフトマックスの近似値バージョンが存在します
Candidate sampling calculates for all the positive labels,
Candidate Sampingは正ラベルをすべて 計算しますが
it randomly samples some negatives.
ランダムサンプリングします
We should greatly reduce computation.
計算を大幅に減らします
The number of negative sampled is
負のサンプル数は
an important hyper parameter to a candidate sampling model.
Candidate Samplingの重要な ハイパーパラメータです
It is always, for obvious reasons, in underestimate.
明白な理由により 常に低く見積もられます
In TensorFlow, we can use the function sample softmax loss.
TensorFlowではsample softmax loss 関数を使えます
Another way to approximate the softmax,
ソフトマックスの近似値を求めるには
is to use noise-contrastive estimation.
Noise-Contrastive Estimationで
Noise-contrastive estimation approximates the denominator the softmax,
出力分布のモデリングを使って
which contains the sum of all the exponentials of the logits,
ソフトマックスの分母の近似値を求めます
by modeling the distribution of outputs instead.
ロジットの指数関数の合計が含まれます
This can provide an approximate less competitionally expensive means,
これにより計算コストが安い近似値算出法で
to find our softmax loss,
損失が見つかります
without having to evaluate every class in the sum of the denominator.
分母の合計で全クラスを評価する必要は ありません
Candidate sampling is more intuitive,
Candidate Samplingは より直感的であり
and doesn't require a really good model.
良好なモデルは不要です
Noise contrastive requires a really good model,
Noise-Contrastiveには良好な モデルが必要です
since it relies on modeling distribution of the outputs.
出力のモデリング分布に依存しているためです
Typically, we will use these functions during training,
トレーニング中にはこうした関数を使用しますが
but for evaluation in inference,
推論の評価では
for better accuracy, we usually use the full softmax.
精度向上のため 完全なソフトマックスを使用します
To do this, make sure to change the default partition strategy,
そのためには既定のパーティション化戦略を
from mode to div,
modeからdivに変更し
for the losses to be consistent between training, evaluation and prediction.
トレーニング、評価、予測間で損失が 一定になるようにします
For our classification output,
この分類出力では
if we have both mutually exclusive labels and probabilities,
ラベルと確率の両方が相互排他的な場合
we should use blank.
＿＿を使用します
If the labels are mutually exclusive,
ラベルが相互排他的で
the probabilities aren't, then we should use blank.
確率はそうでない場合 ＿＿を使用します
If our labels aren't mutually exclusive,
ラベルが相互排他的でない場合
The correct answer is A.
正解はAです
For our classification output,
この分類出力では
if we have both mutually exclusive labels and probabilities,
相互排他的なラベルと確率の両方がある場合
we should use softmax cross entropy with logits version two.
softmax_cross_entropy_with_logits_v2 を使います
This means that there is only one true class for each example,
この場合 各例にtrueクラスは1つしかなく
and we allow for soft labels with the true class,
trueクラスにソフトラベルを与え
does not need to be one hotted for the true class,
trueクラスでのワンホットは不要だが
but can be any combination of values between zero and one for each class,
0と1の間の各クラスの値の組み合わせは その合計が1である限り
as long as they all sum up to one.
どの組み合わせにもなり得ます
If the labels are mutually exclusive,
ラベルが相互排他的で
the probabilities aren't, then we should use sparse softmax cross entropy with logits.
確率が違う場合に使うのは sparse_softmax_cross_entropy_with_logitsです
This doesn't allow for soft labels,
ソフトラベルは使えませんが
but does help produce the model data size,
モデルのデータサイズを生成できます
since you can compress your labels and are just being the index of the true class,
各例のクラス数のベクトルではなく ラベルを圧縮して
rather than a vector of the number of classes for each example.
trueクラスのインデックスにできます
If our labels aren't mutually exclusive,
ラベルが相互排他的でない場合は
we should use sigmoid cross entropy with logits.
softmax_cross_entropy_with_logits を使います
This way, we will get a probability for each possible class,
このように考えうる各クラスの確率を得て
which can give us confidence scores of each class being
各クラスの信頼スコアを得られます
represented in the output such as an image with multiple classes in it,
これは複数のクラスが入っている画像や
or we want to know the existence of each class.
各クラスの存在を知りたい場合に役立ちます